Kunal Parekh

Product Manager

Contact

Address Bengaluru, KA, 560035

Phone +91 997-266-4729

E-mail Kunalparekh27@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/kp27

Website https://parkk27.github.io/

Skills

Research and Trend Analysis

Very Good

Product Marketing

Excellent

Product Development

Very Good

Strategic Planning

Very Good

Budgeting

Good

New features implementation

Very Good

Scrum Methodology

Excellent

Stakeholder Relationship Management

Very Good

Product Management

Very Good

Diligent Senior Product Manager offering 13 years of industry success, including product roadmap development, market research and data analysis. Highly skilled in identifying opportunities to maximize revenue. Driven and strategic with proven history of superior market penetration and product launch ability.

Work History

2017-02- Product Owner

Current

Royal Dutch Shell, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Partnered with business leadership in creating co-founding data team and unlocked power of data that enabled in \$100 million revenue generation to core business.
- Harvested customer needs through interview, data insights to develop & evangelize roadmap and vision to influence in increasing user adoption rate to 15% in quarter.
- Slashed addition cost for change & release process by improving 70% turnaround time to generate \$1 million benefit.
- Managed implementation of new features for supply chain management product by outlining plans and specifications such as how, where and when each component would work.
- Established, initiated, and optimized business development strategies to scale the supply chain product based on business targets, product specifications, market data and budget factors.
- Managed benchmarks, product demonstrations and testimonials for performance evaluation.

2012-05 - Consultant/Product Manager

2017-01

Infosys Limited, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Led discovery, ideation and gathered key stakeholder requirements to define scope of supply chain planner and optimizer product and designed successful translation of not yet well-defined strategic concept into solid working prototype.
- Performed Competitor analysis, customer discovery, gathered feedback from stakeholders, feature prioritization, road mapping for enhancements, managed campaigns through marketing channels and worked on new customer acquisition.
- Conducting qualitative & quantitative use research with 20+ users from different domain by ideation workshop, interviews, and survey to translate into user stories.
- Delivered outstanding service to customers to maintain and extend relationships for future business opportunities.
- Liaised with customers, management, and sales team to better understand customer needs and recommend appropriate solutions.

2007-08 - Senior Product Marketing Engineer

2010-07 Xomox Sanmar Limited, Mumbai, Maharashtra

Mockups and Prototypes Good Self-motivated Professional Very Good Project Management Very Good Supply Chain Solutions Very Good Software JIRA Good Azure DevOps Very Good Slack Very Good Microsoft Office Very Good G Suite Good SQL Good Figma Very Good

- Prepare techno-commercial proposal includes technical bid, Commercial Bid, INCO Terms and comparative analysis.
- Prepare FAB (Feature, Advantage & Benefit) analysis, Cost-Benefit Analysis & Cost of ownership Analysis.

Education

2021-06 -	Post	Graduate	Certificate	Program:	Product	
Current	Management					
	Indian Institute of Management (IIM) - Indore					
2010-06 - 2012-05	MBA: Energy & Infrastructure (Operations)					
	Pandit Deendayal Energy University - Gandhinagar, GJ					
2003-10 - 2007-07	Bachelor of Engineering: Industrial/Production					
	Sardar Patel University - Vallabh Vidyanagar, GJ					
	Sardar Patel University - Vallabh Vidyanagar, GJ					

Certifications

2021-01	Product Masterclass: How to Build Digital Products, Product School
2020-12	Professional Scrum Product Owner II (PSPO 2), scrum.org
2020-11	Digital Product Management Specialization, Coursera
2020-11	Managing Agile Team, Coursera
2020-11	Agile Analytics, Coursera
2020-10	Agile Meets Design Thinking, Coursera
2020-10	Hypothesis Driven Development, Coursera
2020-08	Becoming a Product Manager, LinkedIn
2019-01	Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO1), scrum.org
2017-10	Certification of Capability in Business Analysis™ (CCBA®), IIBA
2017-03	Certified ScrumMaster (CSM), Scrum Alliance

Accomplishments

- Awarded with top rating and consistently performed during my tenure and honored with multiple "Special Recognition Award" and VP CIO awards in Shell & Infosys.
- Presented as speaker in "PetroWorld Conference 2013", August, Mumbai.
- Published and presented writing paper on "Determinants of Economies of Scale & Influence on the Oil & Gas Services: A Discussion" (RIBER) Bangkok June-2012.

Languages

Excellent

Very Good

Very Good

English

Hindi

Gujarati